# 陕西·西安
Xian, Shaanxi
# 不是 4点开门吗 是他家吗
Does the restaurant open at 4 pm? Is that the restaurant we are looking for?
# 看来不仅是我们要找这份猪蹄
We are not the only people looking for the trotter
# 很多人都会早来 等这份猪蹄的
A lot of people are coming earlier and waiting for the trotter
# 因为比平时要晚开门
Because it opens later than the regular time
# 所以呢 门口的队伍就会稍显得壮大一点
So the waiting lines are longer than usual
# 看看这样的长度 好像得等一段时间才能够买得到
We will wait longer to buy it because there are so many people before us
# 分拣猪蹄和肘子
Sorting trotters and pork knuckles
#边捞边卖
selling while sorting
# 这用筷子一插就透了
It is easy to pierce with a chopstick
# 不透的 还得再煮一会儿
Not yet, need longer time to cook it
# 切了
Chopped it
# 给我稍微放一点点汤
I want some broth
# 肘子的话 吃的时候 把汤倒里面
Eat it with the broth when you eat the pork knuckle
# 加热的时候倒里面
Pour it in when you heat it up
# 但是你别倒完 你这汤多 倒完咸了
Don’t add too much broth. Otherwise it will get too salty
# 适量
In a moderate amount
# 猪蹄多少钱一斤了
How much for the trotter?
# 猪蹄40块钱一斤
40 yuan per jin (80 yuan/kg)
# 给我拿两个
Can I have two trotters?
# 切不切
Do you want to have it chopped?
# 切
Yeah
# 两个猪蹄切开
Chopped the two trotters
# 给我放点汤
May I have some broth?
# 汤到里面
Pour the broth in the bag?
# 可以
Sure
# 好大个
So big
# 要了点汤 还是很重的
The bag is heavy with broth in it
# 咱们这次没有要肘子 只是要了猪蹄
We didn’t order pork knuckle this time, just the trotters
# 猪蹄是40块钱一斤
Trotters are 40 yuan per jin
# 我看大家都要汤 所以 我也要了一些
I asked for some broth because everyone did
# 在那边排队的时候你会发现 刚出来的肉
You would find that the meat was pink and cute
# 是粉扑扑的 兜着一股可爱的劲儿
When you were waiting in line
# 肉一旦有了着陆点
Once the pork falls somewhere
# 它的浑身都会颤三颤
It shakes
# 排队的时候 看肘子和猪蹄最爽的时候就是
The best part of watching pork knuckle and trotter when you line up is
# 小哥把肘子的骨头从里面抽出来
Watching that brother draw out the bone from the pork knuckle
# 感觉这块骨头就是卤肉里的卧底 根本不属于这个队伍
The bone is like a spy in the pork knuckle, and belongs nowhere
# 肉能看出来 炖的软烂
We can see the pork is very soft
# 这么吃是稍微有点咸的
It tastes a bit salty when you eat it
# 是 比较咸
Yeah, a little bit salty
# 直接吃是比较咸 我觉得夹馍拌饭是更合适的
I think eating it with buns or rice is better
# 133块钱
133 yuan
# 288元
288 yuan
# 171
171 yuan
# 顾客来买猪蹄和肘子 一般都是100块钱起步
Customers will buy at least 100 yuan of pork knuckle and trotter
# 你能看到 大家拿着猪蹄和肘子都是成袋成袋朝外面走
You can see everyone walking out with many bags of pork knuckle/ trotter
# 即使一天准备200斤的肉 几个小时也就卖光了
It gets sold out very soon even they prepare 200 jin (100 kg) of pork knuckles and trotters